Guide to the Chester DeWitt Pugsley Papers, 1873-1938 and undated, bulk 1925-1938
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Chester DeWitt Pugsley papers 1873-1938 and undated, bulk 1925-1938
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Pugsley, Chester D. (Chester DeWitt), b. 1887.
25.6 Linear Feet 19,216 Items
Lawyer and philanthropist of Peekskill, N.Y.
Personal, business, political, and philanthropic correspondence (chiefly 1925-1938), relating to Pugsley's political work for the Democratic Party, his philanthropic activities, his efforts to promote better understanding and knowledge of international affairs, U.S. and New York politics (1910-1938), and U.S. economic conditions (1920s and 1930s). Correspondents include Roscoe Pound and William Howard Taft.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Chester DeWitt Pugsley Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer from the Duke Law Library in 1959.
Collection Overview
Correspondence, legal papers, press releases, printed material and other miscellaneous papers of Chester DeWitt Pugsley spanning the years 1873-1938, with the majority of the material dating from 1925-1938. Extensive personal, business, political, and philanthropic correspondence (chiefly 1925-1938), relates to Pugsley's political work for the Democratic Party; his philanthropic activities; his efforts to promote better understanding and knowledge of international affairs; his involvement in U.S. and New York politics (1910-1938); and U.S. economic conditions during the 1920s and 1930s, including information on banking. Correspondents include Roscoe Pound and William Howard Taft. Legal papers consist chiefly of typed copies of wills, affidavits, deeds, and trusts relating to Pugsley, the Westchester County National Bank, and various institutional recipients of Pugsley's philanthropy. There are numerous press releases and clippings from news bureaus concerning Pugsley's views on foreign and domestic affairs, his benefactions, institutes and conferences held, and the activities of the American Scenic and Historical Preservation Society. Printed material includes programs of college and university commencements and institutes; notices of stockholders'meetings; advertising circulars; notices of Harvard University class reunions; and papers dealing with national and New York politics in 1916. There are also resolutions relating to world organizations, the Westchester County National Bank, the Church Conference on Social Work, and the College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, Virginia; and scattered minutes of the Peekskill Field Committee, Rollins College, and the League to Enforce Peace. Miscellaneous papers include speeches on domestic and foreign tdpics given by Pugsley.
Arranged in the following series: Correspondence, Legal Papers, Miscellany, and Printed Material. For a more complete description see Davis and Miller, "Guide to the Cataloged Collections in the Manuscript Department of the William R. Perkins Library, Duke University" (1980).
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Pound, Roscoe, 1870-1964
Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930
Democratic Party (N.Y.)
International relations -- Psychological aspects
Philanthropists -- United States -- Correspondence
New York (State) -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950
United States -- Economic conditions
United States -- Politics and government -- 1865-1933
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence Series, 1906-1938 and undated (bulk 1925-1938), (23 boxes)
  - 1906-1926 (Box 1)
  - 1927-1928 (Box 2)
  - 1929 Jan.-May (Box 3)
  - 1929 June-Oct. (Box 4)
  - 1929 Nov.-1930 Jan. 16 (Box 5)
  - 1930 Jan. 17-Feb. 13 (Box 6)
  - 1930 Feb. 14-June (Box 7)
  - 1930 July-Nov. 6 (Box 8)
  - 1930 Nov. 7-1931 Mar. (Box 9)
  - 1931 Apr.-July 9 (Box 10)
  - 1931 July 10-Nov. 10 (Box 11)
  - 1931 Nov. 11-1932 Feb. (Box 12)
  - 1932 Mar.-June 9 (Box 13)
  - 1932 June 10-Sept. 19 (Box 14)
  - 1932 Sept. 20-Dec. (Box 15)
  - 1933 Jan.-June (Box 16)
  - 1933 July-1934 Jan. (Box 17)
  - 1934 Feb.-Sept. (Box 18)
  - 1934 Oct.-1935 July (Box 19)
  - 1935 Aug.-1936 July (Box 20)
  - 1936 Aug.-1937 Feb. (Box 21)
  - 1937 Mar.-Dec. (Box 22)
  - 1938 and undated (Box 23)
  - 1935-1938, correspondence with Wm. Roalfe, Librarian of Duke University Law School
- Legal Papers Series, (1 box)
  - Legal papers (Box 23)
- Miscellany Series, (1 box)
  - Misc. (Box 24)
- Printed Material Series, 1917-1938, (6 boxes)
  - Press Releases (Box 23)
  - Resolutions and Minutes
  - Clippings (Box 25)
    - 1917-1929
    - 1930-1931 (Box 26)
    - 1931-1933 (Box 27)
    - 1933-1934 (Box 28)
    - 1934-1938 (Box 29)
  - Printed Material (Box 30)